NO TAIL TO TELL
말할 꼬리가 없습니다
What if…
만약…
I don't want to be normal?
나는 평범해지고 싶지 않은가?
What?
무엇?
If you're just going to erase my memory
내 기억을 지울 생각이라면
and be the only one who remembers this moment,
그리고 유일한 사람이 되어라 이 순간을 기억하는 사람,
then I should be allowed to do at least this much, right?
그럼 난 할 수 있어야 해 적어도 이 정도죠?
What do you mean…
무슨 뜻이야?
What… do you think you're doing?
뭐… 지금 뭐하고 있는 것 같나요?
Unlike you, I'm not good at doing things half-heartedly.
너와 달리 난 착하지 않아 일을 성심껏 하는 것에.
If I decide to do something, I have to put all my heart into it.
내가 뭔가를 하기로 결정했다면, 온 마음을 다 쏟아야 합니다.
Wait. What do you mean?
기다리다. 무슨 뜻이에요?
Let's date. For real.
데이트하자. 진짜.
I'm serious.
나는 진지하다.
You're still wet behind the ears. Where did you learn to do that?
귀 뒤는 아직 젖어 있어요. 그런 일은 어디서 배웠나요?
What do you think you're doing?
지금 뭐하고 있는 것 같나요?
Why are you so flustered?
왜 그렇게 당황해요?
-Is there a problem? -Of course there is.
- 문제가 있나요? -물론 있습니다.
Once we go back to how we were, we'll never see each other again.
일단 우리의 예전 모습으로 돌아가면, 우리는 다시는 만날 수 없을 거예요.
So you coming on so strong like this
그래서 넌 이렇게 강해지고 있어
is overwhelming.
압도적이다.
Then you shouldn't have led me on.
그렇다면 당신은 나를 이끌지 말았어야 했어요.
I'm just getting started.
이제 막 시작했어요.
Why? Do you want to stop?
왜? 그만하고 싶나요?
When did I ever lead you on?
내가 언제 당신을 이끌었던 적이 있었나요?
Don't think about running, and don't just dip your toes in.
달릴 생각하지 말고, 발가락만 담그지 마세요.
Let's do this right. You and I both.
이것을 올바르게 해보자. 당신과 나 둘 다.
From now on, I'm done joking around.
이제부터 장난은 그만하겠습니다.
EPISODE 9 LOVE ATTACK
에피소드 9 사랑의 공격
That nine-tailed fox.
그 구미호.
She said she became human.
그녀는 인간이 되었다고 말했습니다.
What?
무엇?
She's just an ordinary human now.
그녀는 이제 평범한 인간일 뿐입니다.
An ordinary human?
평범한 인간?
An ordinary human.
평범한 인간.
Then that fox
그럼 그 여우
has no power anymore,
더 이상 힘이 없고,
and there's no reason to be afraid of her.
그리고 그녀를 두려워할 이유가 없습니다.
This just got interesting.
방금 흥미로워졌습니다.
What are you going to do?
당신은 무엇을 할 예정입니까?
-About what? -What do you think?
-무엇에 대해서요? -어떻게 생각하나요?
Now that things are in our favor, you're not going after that damn fox?
이제 상황이 우리에게 유리해졌으니, 넌 그 빌어먹을 여우를 쫓지 않을 거야?
Why should I?
왜 그래야 합니까?
What?
무엇?
Whether I skin it or roast it,
껍질을 벗기든 굽든,
I won't get blood on my hands unless there's something to gain.
손에 피가 묻지 않을 거예요 얻을 것이 없다면 말이죠.
Wait, what does that…
잠깐, 그게 무슨…
They say cultivated beasts have an orb.
사육하는 짐승은 구체를 가지고 있다고 합니다.
Dragons hold dragon orbs to call the wind and rain.
드래곤은 드래곤 오브를 보유하고 있습니다. 바람과 비를 부르게 하소서.
Nine-tailed foxes have fox beads to perform their infinite tricks.
구미호에는 여우구슬이 있어요 무한한 트릭을 수행합니다.
But if that fox really became an ordinary human,
그런데 그 여우라면 정말 평범한 인간이 되었어요
her bead must've already shattered and vanished.
그 사람의 구슬은 이미 깨졌나 봐요 그리고 사라졌다.
So, I'm not interested anymore.
그래서 더 이상 관심이 없습니다.
But look at what we suffered
하지만 우리가 겪은 일을 보세요
because of that damn beast that's not even human!
그 빌어먹을 짐승 때문에 그건 인간도 아니잖아!
We were hiding like rats, cowering in fear!
우리는 쥐처럼 숨어 있었는데, 두려움에 움츠러든다!
Am I the only one who feels like shit?
똥같은 느낌이 드는 건 저뿐인가요?
You all do, don't you?
다들 그렇지 않나요?
Didn't I tell you before?
내가 전에 말하지 않았나요?
A hunter doesn't hunt because of a personal grudge.
사냥꾼은 사냥을 하지 않는다 개인적인 원한 때문에.
Damn you.
젠장.
Wait a second.
잠깐만요.
Then who erased your memory?
그럼 당신의 기억은 누가 지웠나요?
She's an ordinary human now. How could she have erased your memories?
그녀는 이제 평범한 인간입니다. 그녀가 어떻게 당신의 기억을 지울 수 있었나요?
What trick are you trying to pull?
무슨 속임수를 쓰려고 하는 걸까요?
She's not the one
그녀는 그 사람이 아니야
who did it.
누가 그랬어?
Then who was it?
그럼 누구였나요?
I don't know if she was a nine-tailed fox or what,
그녀가 그랬는지는 모르겠지만 꼬리가 구개 달린 여우든 뭐든,
but there was someone else there.
하지만 거기에는 다른 사람이 있었습니다.
Let's date. For real.
데이트하자. 진짜.
I'm serious.
나는 진지하다.
This is driving me nuts.
이것이 나를 미치게 만든다.
What's wrong with me? I couldn't sleep at all.
나에게 무슨 문제가 있습니까? 나는 전혀 잠을 잘 수가 없었다.
And why am I so thirsty?
그런데 나는 왜 이렇게 목이 마르나요?
Gosh.
이런.
I'm dying of thirst, but it's too awkward to go out.
목말라 죽겠다, 그런데 밖에 나가기가 너무 불편해요.
What was I thinking yesterday?
나는 어제 무슨 생각을 하고 있었나요?
Unlike you, I'm not good at doing things half-heartedly.
너와 달리 난 착하지 않아 일을 성심껏 하는 것에.
If I decide to do something, I have to put all my heart into it.
내가 뭔가를 하기로 결정했다면, 온 마음을 다 쏟아야 합니다.
Put all my heart into what?
내 마음을 무엇에 다 쏟아부어요?
Then you shouldn't have led me on.
그렇다면 당신은 나를 이끌지 말았어야 했어요.
I'm just getting started.
이제 막 시작했어요.
What's wrong with me?
나에게 무슨 문제가 있습니까?
I must've lost it.
제가 잃어버린 게 틀림없어요.
She's going to wake up soon.
그녀는 곧 깨어날 것입니다.
It's going to be so awkward. How am I supposed to face her?
너무 어색할 거예요. 내가 그녀를 어떻게 대해야 합니까?
Did he really leave?
그 사람 정말 떠났나요?
This is so awkward.
너무 어색해요.
He could've just played along.
그냥 같이 놀 수도 있었을 텐데.
Why did he suddenly get so bold?
그는 왜 갑자기 그렇게 대담해졌는가?
I didn't expect him to just…
나는 그가 단지…
It caught me off guard.
그것은 나를 경계하게 만들었다.
Oh, crap.
아, 젠장.
Hi, did you sleep well?
안녕, 잘 잤어?
Yeah.
응.
What are you doing?
뭐하세요?
Oh, this…
아, 이거…
Nothing.
아무것도.
I was just picking something up.
방금 뭔가를 줍고 있었어요.
I see.
알겠어요.
Leave or just stay. Make up your mind.
떠나거나 그냥 머무르세요. 결정하세요.
Why do you keep going back and forth? It's confusing.
왜 계속 왔다 갔다 하시나요? 혼란스럽습니다.
Oh, I forgot to give you this.
아, 이걸 주는 걸 깜빡했네요.
I'm heading out to exercise.
운동하러 가는데
I might be late, and you could get hungry.
늦을 수도 있고, 배가 고플 수도 있어요.
You should use this to buy yourself something to eat.
이것을 사용해야합니다 먹을 것을 사려고.
Okay.
좋아요.
But why are you suddenly exercising at the crack of dawn?
그런데 갑자기 왜 그래? 새벽에 운동을 하시나요?
Well,
글쎄,
I recently realized
나는 최근에 깨달았다
that my body's a total wreck right now.
내 몸이 지금 완전히 망가졌다고.
My balance is off, and I don't have any stamina.
잔액이 부족해요 그리고 체력이 없어요.
I see.
알겠어요.
Okay, well…
알았어, 글쎄…
I'm off to work out.
나는 운동하러 나갔다.
Oh, sure.
아, 물론이죠.
-Okay. -Yeah.
-좋아요. -응.
Do you…
당신은…
want to come along?
같이 가고 싶어?
What?
무엇?
Si-yeol.
시열.
The thing is…
문제는…
my memory came back.
기억이 돌아왔습니다.
What are you people planning to do?
너희들은 무엇을 할 계획인가?
You don't have to worry about your friend.
친구에 대해 걱정할 필요가 없습니다.
I'm only interested in the fox bead.
나는 여우구슬에만 관심이 있어요.
It's not like Si-yeol will be in any real danger.
시열같지 않아 진짜 위험에 처하게 될 거예요.
I should just stay out of this.
난 그냥 이 일에서 벗어나야 해요.
Then whatever happens isn't my fault.
그렇다면 무슨 일이 일어나든 내 잘못은 아니다.
But what if they actually kill that nine-tailed fox?
하지만 실제로 사람을 죽인다면 어떨까요? 그 구미호?
Would Si-yeol have to live my life forever?
혹시 시열이? 평생을 살아야 하나?
Gosh.
이런.
Woo-seok.
우석.
Dad.
아빠.
You feeling okay?
기분 괜찮아요?
It's not like I drank last night,
어젯밤에 마신 것 같지는 않은데,
but I don't remember a thing.
하지만 아무것도 기억나지 않아요.
Are you sure you're okay?
정말 괜찮으세요?
Don't even ask.
묻지도 마세요.
Maybe it was all the stress from getting the press to bury the story
그게 다 스트레스였을지도 몰라 언론이 그 이야기를 묻어버리게 만드는 것으로부터
of you beating someone up last week.
당신이 지난 주에 누군가를 때린 것 말이죠.
Man, I totally blacked out.
아, 나 완전 정신이 나갔어.
Is it morning already?
벌써 아침이에요?
Today's the call-up for the international match!
오늘은 소집이야 국제경기를 위해!
-International match? -Man, what time is it?
-국제경기요? - 형, 지금 몇 시야?
We've got to get ready fast.
우리는 빨리 준비해야 해요.
Go wash up. I'll pack your bags.
가서 씻으세요. 내가 당신의 가방을 싸줄게요.
Let's start with some stretching.
스트레칭부터 시작해 볼까요?
-Stretching? -Like this.
-스트레칭? -이와 같이.
Keep your feet straight.
발을 똑바로 유지하십시오.
-Okay. -Good job.
-좋아요. -잘했어요.
-Now go down. Reach. -Okay.
-이제 내려가세요. 도달하다. -좋아요.
Wait, is that it?
잠깐, 그게 다야?
Yeah.
응.
What? Surely not.
무엇? 확실히 그렇지 않습니다.
Let's try again. There's no way a human body can be that stiff.
다시 시도해 보겠습니다. 방법이 없어요 인간의 몸은 그만큼 뻣뻣할 수 있습니다.
What?
무엇?
Now, breathe out.
이제 숨을 내쉬세요.
-I can't go any lower. -That's really it?
- 더 이상 내려갈 수 없어요. - 정말 그렇나요?
-Something's wrong with you. -What?
-뭔가 문제가 생겼어요. -무엇?
Okay, breathe out.
알았어, 숨을 쉬어봐.
Exhale.
내쉬다.
See? You can go lower.
보다? 더 낮게 갈 수 있습니다.
One, two, three, four.
하나, 둘, 셋, 넷.
Breathe out.
숨을 내쉬세요.
-Exhale. -I am!
-내쉬다. -그래요!
Now, the sides. The other side.
이제 측면입니다. 반면.
Exhale.
내쉬다.
Let go, Si-yeol.
놔, 시열아.
-Let go! -You're fine.
-가자! -괜찮아요.
I'm telling you, I'm not!
나는 당신에게 말하고 있습니다. 나는 그렇지 않습니다!
-Stretch! -I'm going to kill you!
-뻗기! -죽여버리겠어!
Good job.
잘했어요.
-Done resting? -What?
-휴식은 끝났나요? -무엇?
-Now, exhale. -Exhale.
- 이제 숨을 내쉬세요. -내쉬다.
-Exhale!
-내쉬다!
Si-yeol, I think I'm done.
시열아, 난 이제 끝난 것 같아.
-What? -I'm done exercising for today.
-무엇? -오늘 운동은 끝났어요.
What are you talking about? We only just finished stretching.
무슨 얘기를 하는 건가요? 이제 막 스트레칭을 마쳤어요.
Let's run a bit.
좀 달리자.
No. You go.
아뇨. 가세요.
I'm going to rest here for a bit.
저는 여기서 잠시 쉴 예정입니다.
Running just makes you sweaty.
달리는 것만으로도 땀이 난다.
That's exactly why you run.
그것이 바로 당신이 달리는 이유입니다.
Look at them running. Don't they look cool?
그들이 달리는 것을 보세요. 멋지지 않나요?
Running will make you feel great.
달리면 기분이 좋아질 것입니다.
Okay, one, two, one, two, one.
좋아, 하나, 둘, 하나, 둘, 하나.
Si-yeol, how far do we have to run?
시열아, 우리 어디까지 달려야 해?
Let's run just up to there. Come on, you can do it!
거기까지만 달려보자. 자, 당신은 할 수 있습니다!
You got this. Let's go!
당신은 이것을 얻었습니다. 갑시다!
That's it.
그게 다야.
Why on earth do humans do this
도대체 인간은 왜 이런 짓을 하는 걸까
instead of using perfectly good cars?
완벽하게 좋은 차를 사용하는 대신?
Isn't this self-torture?
이것은 자기 고문이 아닌가?
Here.
여기.
The water tastes so good, right?
물맛이 너무 좋죠?
Yeah, I feel much better.
응, 기분이 훨씬 좋아졌어.
And the breeze is cool.
그리고 바람이 시원합니다.
Doesn't it feel good?
기분이 좋지 않나요?
I guess.
아마도.
You did great.
정말 잘했어요.
I thought you'd quit halfway, but you stuck with it.
중간에 그만둘 줄 알았는데, 하지만 당신은 그것에 충실했습니다.
This is nothing.
이것은 아무것도 아니다.
Man, it's hot.
아저씨, 더워요.
You'll catch a cold if you take that off now.
감기 걸리겠다 지금 그걸 떼면.
There.
거기.
We're already warmed up. Do you want to do a bit more?
우리는 이미 몸을 녹였습니다. 조금 더 하시겠습니까?
What?
무엇?
Wait. Run more?
기다리다. 더 달려볼까?
No.
아니요.
Let's go play some soccer.
축구하러 가자.
-Do you want to make a bet? -A bet?
-내기를 하시겠습니까? -내기?
If you can take this ball from me, I'll grant you a wish.
나한테서 이 공을 빼앗을 수 있다면, 소원을 들어드릴게요.
-For real? -Of course.
- 진짜요? -물론.
How hard could it be to take the ball from you?
얼마나 힘들겠어요? 너한테서 공을 빼앗으려고?
Anything I want, right? No take-backs.
내가 원하는 건 뭐든지 그렇죠? 테이크백은 없습니다.
Are you even trying?
당신도 노력하고 있나요?
Just you wait.
기다리세요.
Whoa, easy with the hands.
와, 손이 편해요.
Hey.
여기요.
Wait.
기다리다.
Hey, that's a foul!
이봐, 그건 반칙이야!
How is that a foul?
그게 어떻게 반칙이에요?
Here.
여기.
Ok-sun, try harder. Are you giving up already?
옥순아, 더 노력해라. 벌써 포기하고 있나요?
You're wearing knee pads, right?
무릎보호대를 차고 계시죠?
What?
무엇?
-Yes! -Hey, that's a foul.
-예! -야, 그거 반칙이야.
That was really a foul.
그건 정말 반칙이었어요.
-I won, right? -What?
- 내가 이겼지, 그렇지? -무엇?
Why are you staring at me? Is there something on my face?
왜 나를 쳐다보고 있어요? 내 얼굴에 뭔가가 있나요?
No, it's nothing.
아니요, 아무것도 아닙니다.
Want to go again? It's fun now that I took it from you.
다시 가고 싶나요? 지금은 당신에게서 가져간 것이 재미있습니다.
Let's do it. No fouls this time.
해보자. 이번에는 파울이 없습니다.
You too.
너도.
Hey, wait. I said no fouls.
잠깐만요. 나는 파울이 없다고 말했다.
What should I wish for?
나는 무엇을 바라야 하는가?
I've only ever granted wishes. I've never made one myself,
나는 단지 소원을 들어준 적이 있다. 제가 직접 만들어본 적은 없지만,
so I don't know what to ask for.
그래서 무엇을 요구해야할지 모르겠습니다.
Hey, I told you that was a foul.
아, 그건 반칙이라고 내가 말했잖아.
Says who? You didn't say that at the start.
누가 말했어? 처음부터 그런 말은 안 하셨습니다.
Do I really have to explain that kicking someone's shins is a foul?
꼭 설명해야 하나요? 정강이를 차는 것은 반칙이라고요?
Don't be petty. Just admit I won.
사소하게 굴지 마세요. 그냥 내가 이겼다고 인정하세요.
You're a pro. Do you really have to try that hard to beat a regular person?
당신은 프로입니다. 정말 한번 해봐야 되나? 보통 사람을 이기기가 그렇게 어렵나요?
Jeez, you always have a comeback.
이런, 당신은 항상 복귀가 있습니다.
Fine, let's just say you won.
좋아, 그냥 네가 이겼다고 치자.
Yes!
예!
-Give me your hand. -What?
- 손을 내밀어 보세요. -무엇?
We're on a date right now.
우리 지금 데이트 중이에요.
I just want to hold hands while we walk.
그냥 걷는 동안 손을 잡고 싶어요.
So, what should we do when we get home?
그래서, 우리 집에 가면 뭘 해야 하지?
Actually, I'm not going home. I've got to go train right away.
사실 집에 안 갈 거예요. 지금 당장 기차로 가야 해요.
What do you mean? We've been working out this whole time.
무슨 뜻이에요? 우리는 내내 운동을 해왔습니다.
That was just my own workout. Now I have to train with the team.
그것은 단지 나만의 운동이었습니다. 이제 팀과 함께 훈련해야 해요.
Why bother? It won't matter once we go back.
왜 귀찮게? 일단 돌아가면 상관없어요.
I have to make money.
돈을 벌어야 해요.
They said I need to win matches to get paid a decent amount.
그들은 내가 경기에서 이겨야 한다고 말했어 적당한 금액을 받으려면.
Plus, we don't have much to do right now.
게다가 지금 당장은 할 일이 별로 없어요.
Don't we have to wait until that chairman actually hands over the building?
그 회장님까지 기다려야 하는 거 아닌가요 실제로 건물을 넘겨주나요?
Well, yeah.
글쎄요.
After I get my win bonus from this weekend's match,
승리 보너스를 받은 후 이번 주말 경기부터
I'll treat you to something nice. Something better than pork cutlets.
내가 좋은 걸 대접해줄게. 돈까스보다 뭔가 더 맛있네요.
No, wait.
아니, 잠깐만요.
Eun-ho, should we go on a trip?
은호야, 우리 여행 갈까?
A trip? Just like that?
여행? 그냥 그런가요?
Well, the match this weekend is in Suncheon.
음, 이번 주말에 경기가 있어 순천에 있어요.
I heard the reed fields are nice there.
거기 갈대밭이 좋다고 들었어.
We could go together, look around, and get something nice to eat.
같이 가서 둘러볼 수도 있고, 그리고 맛있는 것 좀 사오세요.
How about it?
어때요?
Sure, whatever.
물론이죠.
That's a promise.
그것은 약속입니다.
Then, you should go home and rest.
그럼 집에 가서 쉬어야지.
You must be tired from all that exercise.
그 모든 운동으로 피곤하시겠군요.
Actually, I just remembered I have something to do today.
사실 방금 기억났어 오늘 할 일이 있어요.
What is it?
그것은 무엇입니까?
We need money for the trip. I'll make some while you train.
여행을 가려면 돈이 필요해요. 네가 훈련하는 동안 내가 좀 만들어줄게.
-You? -I told you.
-너? -내가 말했잖아.
You should just focus on soccer
넌 축구에만 집중해야 해
because I'll bring home tons of money.
왜냐면 내가 집에 엄청난 돈을 가져올 것이기 때문이다.
INTERNATIONAL SOCCER
국제 축구
-Hello, sir. -Hello!
-안녕하세요 선생님. -안녕하세요!
-Congratulations. We love you. -Congratulations.
-축하해요. 우리는 당신을 사랑합니다. -축하해요.
Mr. Hyeon, congratulations on the transfer.
현 씨, 이적을 축하합니다.
Are you settling in okay?
잘 적응하고 계시나요?
Pardon?
뭐라고요?
I mean, since you've transferred.
내 말은, 당신이 이적한 이후로요.
I see.
알겠어요.
Well, I'm still settling in.
글쎄요, 아직 적응 중이에요.
Why are you so nervous? It's not like you.
왜 그렇게 긴장해요? 당신과는 다릅니다.
Woo-seok.
우석.
How have you been?
잘 지내셨나요?
-Yeah. -Congratulations on the transfer, man.
-응. - 이적 축하해요.
Why are you only filming Woo-seok? Get me too.
왜 우석씨만 찍나요? 나도 잡아라.
Come on, he's world-class.
어서요, 그는 세계적 수준이에요.
Man, that's harsh.
정말 가혹한 일이군요.
Hey, why haven't you been answering my DMs?
이봐, 왜 안 가봤어? 내 DM에 답장해?
You mean… I haven't been?
그러니까... 난 가본 적 없어?
Look at him, acting all distant.
그 사람을 좀 봐, 모두 멀리 떨어져 행동.
This is how people change when they make it big.
사람이 이렇게 변하는구나 그들이 그것을 크게 만들 때.
You need to get this on camera.
이걸 카메라에 담아야 해요.
Woo-seok!
우석!
-Hello.
-안녕하세요.
-Am I invisible to you guys?
-나는 너희들에게 보이지 않는 걸까?
Woo-seok was just so blinding. I didn't even see you.
우석은 정말 눈이 멀었다. 나는 당신을 보지도 못했습니다.
Good to see you.
만나서 반가워요.
-How have you been? -Good.
- 잘 지냈어요? -좋은.
Woo-seok, I'll see you later.
우석아, 나중에 보자.
We're always rooting for you.
우리는 항상 당신을 응원합니다.
Thanks.
감사해요.
COOKING, FOOD SERVICE
요리, 음식 서비스
STORE MANAGEMENT, SALES
매장 관리, 판매
Let's see. What should I do to make money?
어디 보자. 돈을 벌려면 어떻게 해야 하나요?
Oh, this hourly pay isn't bad.
아, 이 시급 나쁘지 않네요.
Do you have a problem with my resume?
내 이력서에 문제가 있나요?
Education?
교육?
OFFICE WORK, SALES, EDUCATION
사무, 판매, 교육
It's Yukyeong Gongwon, the Royal College.
왕립대학 유경공원 입니다.
It was Korea's first modern educational institution.
한국 최초였죠 현대 교육 기관.
You've never heard of it?
들어본 적도 없나요?
Not Sungkyunkwan University. Seonggyungwan National Academy.
성균관대학교는 아닙니다. 국립성균관학원.
Seonggyungwan never handed out diplomas.
성균관은 졸업장을 나눠준 적이 없다.
Certifications? Look, even without them,
인증? 보세요, 그것들이 없어도
there's nothing I can't do or haven't done--
내가 할 수 없는 일은 아무것도 없어 아니면 아직 하지 않았나요?
Hello?
안녕하세요?
Why are they so picky about hiring just a part-timer?
왜 이렇게 까다로워? 그냥 파트타임으로 고용하는 건 어때요?
OH SEASON GROCERY STORE NOW HIRING
OH SEASON 식료품점 채용 중
"No qualifications required."
"자격은 필요하지 않습니다."
"No experience required, and no age limit"?
"경험이 필요하지 않습니다. 그리고 나이 제한도 없어"?
What the heck? Why isn't anyone here?
도대체 뭐야? 왜 여기에 아무도 없나요?
Push up a little more.
조금 더 밀어 올려보세요.
SI-YEOL
시열
Where are you?
당신은 어디에 있습니까?
Jeez. Hello?
이런. 안녕하세요?
-Hey, where are you guys? -Hey, Si-yeol.
-야, 너희들 어디 있어? -안녕, 시열.
Why aren't you here? Isn't it training time?
왜 여기 없나요? 훈련시간 아닌가?
What are you talking about? Training was canceled.
무슨 얘기를 하는 건가요? 훈련이 취소되었습니다.
You didn't get the message earlier?
아까 메시지를 받지 못하셨나요?
Tell Si-yeol to come.
시열이한테 오라고 해주세요.
Hey, you want to join us? We're at the internet cafe out front.
이봐, 우리랑 같이 갈래? 우리는 앞에 있는 인터넷 카페에 있어요.
We have a match this weekend. Why did they cancel training?
이번 주말에 경기가 있어요. 훈련을 취소한 이유는 무엇입니까?
Never mind. Just get over here.
괜찮아요. 그냥 여기로 오세요.
Let's train by ourselves.
스스로 훈련해보자.
Hello… Hello?
안녕하세요… 안녕하세요?
-Hel… -Don't you dare--
-헬… -감히 그러지 마세요--
Man, I can't hear a thing.
아, 아무것도 안 들려요.
Man, he's exhausting.
그 사람 정말 지쳤어요.
-Why? -He wants us to come and train on our own.
-왜? -그는 우리가 와서 스스로 훈련하기를 원합니다.
Jeez, just hearing that makes me tired.
이런, 듣기만 해도 피곤해지네요.
I could go for an iced Americano.
아이스 아메리카노를 마시러 갈 수도 있겠네요.
Iced Americano? It's freezing out.
아이스아메리카노? 꽁꽁 얼고 있어요.
Have this instead.
대신 이걸 드세요.
Quick, give me one.
빨리, 하나 주세요.
I feel awake now.
이제 깨어난 것 같아요.
It's good.
좋다.
I feel like someone's been watching me from behind for a while now.
누군가 나를 지켜보고 있는 것 같은 느낌이 들어요 지금은 잠시 뒤에서.
What?
무엇?
Don't you guys feel anything weird?
여러분 뭔가 이상한 느낌이 들지 않으세요?
You know, like someone's keeping an eye on us.
알다시피, 누군가의 것 처럼 우리를 지켜보고 있습니다.
Who would be looking at us?
누가 우리를 쳐다보겠습니까?
Come on, you're not that famous. Don't be so full of yourself.
어서요, 당신은 그렇게 유명하지 않아요. 자신으로 가득 차 있지 마십시오.
-You think so? -Beom, our base is getting wrecked!
- 그렇게 생각해요? -범아, 우리 기지가 망가지고 있어!
Oh, shoot! What the… Hey!
아, 쏴! 뭐야… 이봐!
-Hey. -Man.
-여기요. -남성.
I did warn you.
나는 당신에게 경고했다.
OH SEASON GROCERY STORE
오 시즌 식료품점
STANDARD EMPLOYMENT CONTRACT EUN-HO
표준 고용 계약 은호
So, what's your name?
그래서, 당신의 이름은 무엇입니까?
Eun-ho.
은호.
RESIDENT REGISTRATION CARD KIM OK-SUN
주민등록카드 김옥선
EUN-HO
은호
It doesn't say that here.
여기서는 그런 말을 하지 않습니다.
Ms. Kim Ok-sun, this is an employment contract.
김옥순 선생님, 이것은 고용 계약입니다.
You have to write your real name.
실명을 적어주셔야 합니다.
How many times do I have to say it? That's the fake name.
몇 번이나 말해야 합니까? 그거 가짜 이름이에요.
Eun-ho is my real name.
은호는 내 본명이에요.
EUN-HO
은호
KIM OK-SUN
김옥선
You know, Ms. Kim Ok-sun, you're being a little too casual.
아시죠, 김옥순 선생님, 당신은 좀 너무 캐주얼한 것 같아요.
-What? -Stop speaking informally to me.
-무엇? - 나한테 반말은 그만둬라.
What are you good at, Ms. Ok-sun?
옥순씨는 무엇을 잘하시나요?
You were speaking informally too just now.
방금도 너도 반말을 하고 있었잖아.
Excuse me?
실례합니다?
Nothing. Fine.
아무것도 아님. 괜찮은.
It won't be easy, but I'll take it as a unique experience.
쉽지 않을 거예요, 하지만 나는 그것을 독특한 경험으로 받아들일 것이다.
I'm good at everything. There really isn't anything I can't do.
나는 모든 것을 잘한다. 정말 할 수 없는 일이 없어요.
Oh, really? We've got an ace here.
오, 진짜? 여기에 에이스가 있습니다.
Do you like plushies?
인형 좋아하시나요?
Oh my. How cute.
아, 이런. 얼마나 귀엽습니까?
Why'd you take that? Throw it away.
그걸 왜 가져간 거야? 그것을 버리십시오.
Damn it.
젠장.
Seriously?
진지하게?
I don't want it.
나는 그것을 원하지 않습니다.
Hey, you!
이봐, 너!
-Wow! -What's that?
-우와! - 그게 뭐죠?
Stay back! Don't come here. Go away!
물러서세요! 여기 오지 마세요. 저리 가요!
Hey, stop! It'll come off!
그만해! 벗겨질 거야!
DAEHEUNG CITIZENS FC
대흥시티즌스FC
Oh gosh, sir…
맙소사, 선생님...
Why are you here?
당신은 왜 여기에 있습니까?
Coach, I knocked a bunch of times.
코치님, 제가 여러 번 노크를 했어요.
What do you want?
당신은 무엇을 원하세요?
Is today's training really canceled?
오늘 훈련 정말 취소됐나요?
Yeah. Didn't you get the message?
응. 메시지를 받지 못하셨나요?
What we need is more practice, so how could you…
우리에게 필요한 것은 더 많은 연습이다. 그런데 어떻게…
Man.
남자.
Wait. What is that smell?
기다리다. 그 냄새는 무엇입니까?
Coach, were you drinking?
코치님, 술 마셨어요?
The match is right around the corner,
경기가 코앞으로 다가왔습니다.
but you canceled practice, and now this?
그런데 연습을 취소했는데 이제 이게?
Gosh, I'm hungover.
맙소사, 나 배고파.
Si-yeol, did you eat yet?
시열아, 밥은 먹었어?
Pardon?
뭐라고요?
Let's go grab a bite.
한 입 먹으러 가자.
Gosh.
이런.
-What is this? -It's totally burnt.
-이게 뭔가요? -완전히 불탔어요.
You expect us to eat this?
우리가 이걸 먹을 거라고 생각하는 거야?
Should I throw it away then? That's wasteful.
그러면 버려야 할까요? 그것은 낭비입니다.
Man, I burnt another one.
아, 또 하나 태웠어요.
It's because you kept talking to me.
당신이 나에게 계속 말을 걸었기 때문이에요.
Just eat and move along.
그냥 먹고 움직이세요.
I'm not buying this.
나는 이것을 사지 않을 것이다.
Maybe this is a bit too burnt.
어쩌면 이건 좀 너무 탄 것 같아요.
Don't cause trouble this time.
이번엔 문제를 일으키지 마세요.
Got it, Ms. Kim Ok-sun?
알겠습니다, 김옥순 씨?
This is much better.
이것이 훨씬 낫습니다.
They should've put me on this from the start.
날 가두었어야 했는데 처음부터 이것에 대해.
Come over here! I'll ring you up.
여기로 오세요! 전화할게요.
What?
무엇?
I don't think the discount was applied.
할인이 적용되지 않은 것 같아요.
-What? -Look, right here.
-무엇? -보세요, 바로 여기요.
You need to ring it up again.
다시 전화를 걸어야 합니다.
Jeez.
이런.
CHECK RECEIPT, CHECK PRICE
영수증 확인, 가격 확인
Cancel…
취소…
Look, I don't know how to cancel this.
이거 취소하는 방법을 모르겠어요.
-Can't we just let it slide? -Excuse me?
- 그냥 놔두면 안 되나요? -실례합니다?
Also, I like being cashier, so don't file a complaint.
그리고 저는 계산원이 되는 걸 좋아해요. 그러니 불만을 제기하지 마세요.
-Let's keep this between us. -That's ridiculous--
-이건 우리끼리만 간직하자. -말도 안 되는 소리야--
Just consider the 1,750 won as a donation.
1,750원을 기부금으로 생각해보세요.
It'll bring you good luck.
그것은 당신에게 행운을 가져다 줄 것입니다.
I knew it was going too smoothly.
나는 그것이 너무 순조롭게 진행되고 있다는 것을 알았습니다.
Gosh, this is chaos.
맙소사, 이건 혼돈이다.
Maybe I should've just let them complain.
어쩌면 그들이 불평하도록 내버려두었어야 했을지도 모릅니다.
Excuse me.
실례합니다.
A check?
수표?
You don't have cash or a card?
현금이나 카드가 없나요?
Why? Is there a problem?
왜? 문제가 있나요?
Just use a card. I don't know how to process that.
그냥 카드를 사용하세요. 나는 그것을 처리하는 방법을 모른다.
If you have a problem with that, you should file a complaint.
그것에 문제가 있다면, 불만을 제기해야 합니다.
-Excuse me? -A complaint.
-실례합니다? - 불만이요.
Ma'am, let me help you with that.
부인, 제가 도와드릴께요.
Just press this, and then this for checks.
이것을 누르고 확인을 위해 이것을 누르십시오.
Get a signature on the back and give her the change.
뒷면에 서명을 받으세요 그리고 그녀에게 잔돈을 주세요.
Okay. Thanks.
좋아요. 감사해요.
Sorry about that.
죄송해요.
You're not drinking, right?
너 술 안 마시는 거 맞지?
No.
아니요.
Gosh.
이런.
Who drinks soju like it's water?
소주를 물처럼 마시는 사람이 있나요?
What's going on?
무슨 일이야?
Hey, Si-yeol.
안녕하세요, 시열님.
We're done for.
이제 끝났습니다.
What do you mean?
무슨 뜻이에요?
I'm talking about our team, you punk.
우리 팀 얘기하는 거야, 이 새끼야.
Come on, Coach.
어서요, 코치님.
We're last in the fourth division. We can't get any lower.
우리는 4부 리그에서 꼴찌입니다. 우리는 더 이상 낮아질 수 없습니다.
How can we be "done for"?
우리는 어떻게 "끝났을" 수 ​​있습니까?
I told you, I'll get us promoted.
내가 말했잖아, 우리를 승진시켜주겠다고.
Promotion doesn't even matter.
승진도 상관없어요.
You know
알잖아
the director who sponsors us, right?
우리를 후원하는 감독님 맞죠?
The director at my grandma's nursing home?
우리 할머니 요양원 원장?
Yes, him.
응, 그 사람.
Well, that director said
그런데 그 감독님이 그러시더라고요.
he can't sponsor us anymore.
그는 더 이상 우리를 후원할 수 없습니다.
What?
무엇?
A sponsorship contract isn't a joke.
스폰서십 계약이 장난이 아니군요.
He can't just break it overnight.
그는 하룻밤 사이에 그것을 깨뜨릴 수 없습니다.
Well, what else can we do?
그럼 우리가 또 무엇을 할 수 있나요?
Like you said, we're in the fourth division.
당신이 말했듯이, 우리는 4부 리그에 있어요.
It's not exactly good publicity to sponsor the last-place team.
홍보가 별로 좋지 않은데 꼴찌 팀을 후원하기 위해
The director was just sponsoring us for years
감독 몇 년 동안 우리를 후원하고 있었을 뿐인데
as a service to the community because he liked soccer.
지역사회에 대한 봉사로서 왜냐하면 그는 축구를 좋아했기 때문이다.
But he said he can't afford it anymore, so there's nothing we can do.
하지만 그 사람은 더 이상 그럴 여유가 없다고 하더군요. 그러니 우리가 할 수 있는 일은 아무것도 없습니다.
Then,
그런 다음,
what do we do now?
이제 우리는 무엇을 하나요?
What happens to the team?
팀은 어떻게 되나요?
We have to find a new sponsor.
새로운 스폰서를 찾아야 해요.
It won't be easy, though.
하지만 쉽지는 않을 것입니다.
We're not going down like this.
우리는 이렇게 추락하지 않습니다.
No, I mean
아니, 내 말은
what happens if we don't find one?
우리가 찾지 못하면 어떻게 되나요?
What do you think, you punk?
어떻게 생각해, 이 새끼야?
The club goes bankrupt, and the team disbands.
클럽이 파산하고, 그리고 팀은 해산된다.
Forget about paying the players.
선수들에게 돈을 지불하는 것을 잊어버리세요.
We can't even pay the rent for the training ground.
우리는 집세도 낼 수 없어 훈련장을 위해.
What can we do?
우리는 무엇을 할 수 있나요?
Don't tell the other guys, okay?
다른 남자들한테는 말하지 마, 알았지?
I shouldn't have even told you.
난 너한테 말하지 말았어야 했는데.
I just had to get it off my chest.
그냥 가슴에서 꺼내야 했어요.
I've been thinking.
나는 생각해왔다.
I don't think you're a good fit for our store.
내 생각엔 아닌 것 같아 당신은 우리 가게에 잘 맞는 사람이에요.
I'll pay you for your work today,
오늘 일한 대가는 내가 지불할게.
but you don't need to come in anymore.
하지만 더 이상 들어올 필요는 없습니다.
Really? That's fine.
정말? 괜찮습니다.
The pay was too low for the workload anyway.
급여가 너무 적었어요 어쨌든 작업량을 위해.
I'm sorry to bother you,
귀찮게 해서 미안해요,
but the totals aren't adding up.
하지만 합계가 합산되지 않습니다.
What?
무엇?
Ms. Kim's cash drawer is off.
김 씨의 금전함이 꺼져 있습니다.
What did I just do?
내가 방금 무슨 짓을 한 거지?
You gave the customer back her 100,000-won check and the change.
당신은 고객에게 돌려주었습니다 그녀의 10만원 수표와 잔돈.
That explains why we're exactly 100,000 won short.
그게 설명이야 왜 우리에겐 정확히 10만원이 부족한지.
So, what happens to me?
그러면 나는 어떻게 되나요?
It's okay.
괜찮아요.
Mistakes happen. Don't worry about it.
실수가 발생합니다. 걱정하지 마세요.
Really?
정말?
Of course.
물론.
Just pay it back. No big deal.
그냥 갚으세요. 별거 아니야.
What?
무엇?
Your hourly pay is 10,030 won,
시급은 10,030원이고,
and you worked for five hours, so that's 50,150 won for today.
그리고 다섯 시간 동안 일했고, 그럼 오늘은 50,150원이군요.
But with the 100,000 won loss,
하지만 10만원 손실로
you just owe us 49,850 won.
당신은 우리에게 49,850원의 빚을 졌습니다.
Owe you?
빚진 거야?
You mean you're not even paying me,
나한테 돈도 안 갚는단 말이에요.
but I have to pay you 49,850 won?
그런데 49,850원을 갚아야 한다고?
I worked like a dog all day for this place!
나는 개처럼 일했다 하루 종일 이 곳을 위해!
That's too bad.
안됐네요.
I walked here just to save bus fare!
버스비 아끼려고 여기까지 걸어왔어요!
Can't you let this slide?
이 슬라이드를 놔둘 수 없나요?
I can't do that. I'm just an employee here.
나는 그렇게 할 수 없습니다. 저는 그냥 여기 직원이에요.
I bragged about bringing home money.
나는 집에 돈을 가져왔다고 자랑했다.
What do I tell Si-yeol?
시열이한테 뭐라고 말해야 하나요?
I can't say I worked all day just to end up in debt.
하루종일 일했다고는 말할 수 없어 그냥 빚을 지게 됩니다.
Should I sell the clothes?
옷을 팔아야 하나?
-Si-yeol, you're home! -Yeah.
- 시열아, 집에 왔구나! -응.
-What's wrong? -What?
- 무슨 일이야? -무엇?
I mean, you went to training, and you're back looking so dejected again.
훈련에 갔다고 하더군요. 그리고 당신은 다시 너무 낙담한 모습으로 돌아왔네요.
Well, that's…
글쎄요...
It's nothing. The team's just having some issues.
그것은 아무것도 아니다. 팀에 문제가 좀 있어요.
Si-yeol, want me to cheer you up?
시열아, 내가 응원해줄까?
All of a sudden?
갑자기?
Here. I made some money.
여기. 나는 돈을 좀 벌었습니다.
Wow, it's pretty thick.
와, 꽤 두꺼워요.
-How much is this? -It's 200,000 won. I did good, right?
-이거 얼마예요? - 20만원이에요. 난 잘했어, 그렇지?
Wait, what did you do to get 200,000 won in a day?
잠깐, 무슨 짓을 한 거야? 하루에 20만원 벌려면?
You didn't steal this, did you?
당신은 이것을 훔친 것이 아니죠?
I'm on a mission to do good deeds right now.
나는 임무를 수행 중이야 지금 당장 좋은 일을 하려고.
How can you say that to someone who's trying to live right?
어떻게 그런 말을 할 수 있니? 올바르게 살려고 노력하는 사람에게?
I know. You're right.
알아요. 당신 말이 맞아요.
But where did you earn this much in a--
그런데 넌 어디서 이렇게 많은 돈을 벌었지?
I've got skills. I've been around the block, you know.
나는 기술을 가지고 있습니다. 나는 한 블록을 돌아다녔습니다.
The details are a trade secret.
자세한 내용은 영업비밀입니다.
You haven't eaten yet, right? Let's go out. It's my treat.
아직 식사도 안 하신 거죠? 나가자. 내 선물이야.
I told you to fix your doorbell already.
내가 이미 초인종을 고치라고 했잖아요.
-Oh, hello. -Hello.
-아, 안녕하세요. -안녕하세요.
What are you guys doing here?
너희들은 여기서 뭐하는거야?
Did you guys hear something?
뭔가 들으셨나요?
Hear what?
무엇을 들어요?
The international match is today.
오늘 국제 경기가 있어요.
We came to watch it together.
우리는 그것을 함께 보러 왔습니다.
Hello, Eun-ho.
안녕하세요, 은호님.
Hey!
여기요!
Eun-ho, you haven't tried my family's galbi, right?
은호야 넌 해본 적도 없어 우리 가족 갈비 맞죠?
Jeong-bae's folks bought a building selling this galbi.
정배의 사람들 이 갈비 파는 건물을 샀어요.
It's good.
좋다.
Really? I haven't had beef galbi in a while.
정말? 저는 쇠고기갈비를 먹어본 적이 없어요. 잠시 후.
Why couldn't you guys just watch the game at home?
너희들은 왜 못했니? 그냥 집에서 경기나 볼까?
Come on, don't be like that.
자, 그렇게 하지 마세요.
We always watch the international games here together.
우리는 항상 지켜본다 국제 게임이 여기 함께 있어요.
Aren't you glad we're here, Eun-ho?
우리가 여기 있어서 기쁘지 않니, 은호?
Of course. Beef galbi is always welcome.
물론. 쇠고기갈비는 언제나 환영입니다.
-Let's eat.
- 먹자.
How can you call yourself an athlete when you're drinking this late?
어떻게 자신을 운동선수라고 부를 수 있나요? 이렇게 늦게까지 술을 마셔?
Again with the nagging.
다시 잔소리로.
You don't have to drink.
술을 마실 필요는 없습니다.
Today's a good day, so how about just one, okay?
오늘은 좋은 날이야, 그럼 하나만 어때요?
Would you like a glass, Eun-ho?
은호 씨, 한잔 드릴까요?
Sure, pour me one.
물론이죠. 하나 부어주세요.
Okay, fine.
알았어, 알았어.
What's the point of nagging you guys anyway?
잔소리하는 게 무슨 소용이야 어쨌든 너희들?
Just don't overdo it.
과용하지 마세요.
Okay!
좋아요!
Nice seeing you again, Eun-ho.
다시 만나서 반가워요, 은호님.
-Nice to see you! -Cheers!
-만나서 반가워요! -건배!
You know, it's really weird.
정말 이상해요.
What is?
무엇인가요?
Actually, since yesterday…
사실 어제부터...
Man, it's getting chilly. I might catch a cold.
아저씨, 날씨가 점점 추워지고 있어요. 감기에 걸릴 수도 있어요.
They must've fixed the streetlight.
그 사람들이 가로등을 고쳤나 봐요.
It had been left broken for months.
몇 달 동안 깨진 채로 방치되어 있었습니다.
What the…
무슨…
Who is it?
누구입니까?
You were stalked?
스토킹당했어요?
Who'd stalk you?
누가 당신을 스토킹하겠어요?
I know how crazy it sounds--
얼마나 말도 안 되는 소리인지 알아요.
Beom, were you up all night gaming again?
범야 또 밤새 게임했어?
It's because you're tired, that's all.
피곤해서 그런 거야, 그게 다야.
See? You've got dark circles under your eyes.
보다? 다크서클이 생겼어요 당신의 눈 아래.
That's…
그건…
just because I'm stressed out.
그냥 스트레스 받아서요.
Why are you stressed?
왜 스트레스를 받나요?
Bet his stocks tanked again.
그의 주식이 다시 폭락할 것이라고 장담했다.
How's that my fault? The domestic market is a total mess.
그게 어떻게 내 잘못이야? 국내 시장은 그야말로 난장판이다.
I thought Si-yeol was the only one broke, but you're penniless too, aren't you?
시열이만 망가진 줄 알았는데, 하지만 너 역시 무일푼이구나, 그렇지?
Come on, I'm different from Si-yeol.
자, 저는 시열이랑 달라요.
He's all about soccer without a plan,
계획 없이 축구만 하는 사람인데,
and I ended up like this trying to prepare for the future.
그리고 난 결국 이렇게 됐어 미래를 준비하려고 노력합니다.
What is it?
그것은 무엇입니까?
What was that just now?
방금 그거 뭐였지?
Something flashed. Was it lightning?
뭔가 번쩍였다. 번개였나요?
But the sky is clear.
하지만 하늘은 맑습니다.
Si-yeol.
시열.
Come out for a second.
잠시만 나오세요.
What's the matter all of a sudden?
갑자기 무슨 일이야?
Come out. How long are you going to hide?
나오세요. 언제까지 숨어 있을 건가요?
What?
무엇?
Hello, sis.
안녕, 언니.
-It's me, Secretary Choi. -Come in.
-나야, 최비서. - 들어오세요.
Hey.
안녕.
Congratulations on returning home, sir.
귀국을 축하드립니다, 선생님.
Honestly, I've always hated this place because my old man was here.
솔직히 난 예전부터 이곳이 싫었어 왜냐하면 내 할아버지가 여기 계셨거든요.
It was more fun out there.
거기가 더 재미있었어요.
But you know, after wandering around,
그런데 여기저기 돌아다니다가
there really is no place like home.
정말 집만한 곳이 없어요.
After ten years, it was even nice to see my father.
10년 후, 아버지를 만나서 반가웠어요.
Are you back for good now, sir?
이제 완전히 돌아오셨나요?
Of course. No need for me to run anymore.
물론. 더 이상 달릴 필요가 없습니다.
Anyway, what's that damn shaman up to?
그나저나 저 망할 무당은 뭐하는 걸까요?
He's searching every antique shop and bookstore in the country.
그는 매일 검색하고 있어요 시골의 골동품 가게와 서점.
Seems like he's looking for something.
뭔가를 찾고 있는 것 같습니다.
He told me to wait and do nothing, but what the hell is he doing?
아무것도 하지 말고 기다리라고 하더군요. 그런데 그 사람 대체 뭐하는 거야?
I need him to catch that other fox
다른 여우를 잡으려면 그 사람이 필요해요
so I can get on with my business, damn it.
그래야 내 일을 계속할 수 있지, 젠장.
Also, the fourth-division soccer matter is proceeding as you've requested.
또한 4부 리그 축구 문제 요청하신 대로 진행 중입니다.
Oh, really?
오, 진짜?
How are you proceeding with it?
어떻게 진행하고 있나요?
I found corruption and nepotism at the sponsoring nursing home
부패와 족벌주의를 발견했어요 후원요양원에서
tied to its founding family.
창립 가족과 연결되어 있습니다.
I told them to choose between the whole family going to jail
선택하라고 했더니 온 가족이 감옥에 가는 사이
or ending the sponsorship.
또는 후원을 종료합니다.
They should've announced the termination of the sponsorship by now.
발표했어야 했는데 이제 후원이 종료됩니다.
Good job.
잘했어요.
How did you know I was here?
내가 여기 있다는 걸 어떻게 알았나요?
That light earlier. You gained spiritual power, didn't you?
아까 그 빛. 영적인 힘을 얻었죠?
-Really? -Yeah.
-정말? -응.
Yes, I did. I got a huge amount of spiritual power.
네, 그랬어요. 나는 엄청난 영적인 힘을 얻었습니다.
A few more times like this, and I'll have nine tails in no time.
이런 식으로 몇 번 더, 그리고 곧 9개의 꼬리를 갖게 될 거예요.
That old man, Chairman Kim, worked fast.
그 노인, 김 위원장은 일을 빨리 했어요.
Anyway, why were you hiding there?
그런데 왜 거기 숨어 있었나요?
You could've just said you were here.
그냥 여기 있었다고 말할 수도 있었을 텐데.
Pardon?
뭐라고요?
Was it because of the guys inside?
안에 있는 놈들 때문이었을까?
Since when did she have that kind of tact?
언제부터 그런 재치가 있었나요?
How long have you been there?
거기에 얼마나 오래 있었나요?
Well, since the beginning?
음, 처음부터?
You're acting suspicious.
당신은 의심스러운 행동을 하고 있습니다.
Hold on.
기다리다.
You weren't here for us, were you?
당신은 우리를 위해 여기 온 것이 아니었죠, 그렇죠?
Don't tell me you're the one stalking that stock junkie?
당신이 바로 그 사람이라고 말하지 마세요 그 주식 중독자를 스토킹한다고요?
Yes.
예.
What?
무엇?
Man, we're out of sauce.
이봐, 소스가 떨어졌어.
Our beef galbi is already seasoned.
우리 쇠고기갈비는 이미 양념이 되어있습니다.
It tastes better just as it is.
그대로 드시면 더 맛있습니다.
No, I like the sauce. I'll go buy some.
아니요, 소스가 마음에 들어요. 좀 사러 갈게요.
Are you crazy?
제정신이에요?
I should just eat it as is, right?
그냥 그대로 먹어야겠죠?
I was wondering if we did something wrong,
우리가 뭔가 잘못한 게 아닐까 싶었는데,
but I guess it was Si-yeol who messed up.
하지만 내 생각엔 망친 건 시열이었다.
It's not good to get involved in a couple's fight.
엮이는 건 좋지 않아 부부싸움 중.
Maybe we should've left earlier.
어쩌면 우리는 더 일찍 떠났어야 했을지도 모릅니다.
Well, it's not too late.
글쎄, 아직 늦지 않았어.
You want to go past them while they're going at each other?
당신은 그들을 지나치고 싶어 그들이 서로 가는 동안?
I don't think that's a good idea.
나는 그것이 좋은 생각이라고 생각하지 않습니다.
-We're totally trapped here. -Yeah.
-우린 여기에 완전히 갇혔어요. -응.
Just turn on the TV. The match is about to start anyway.
TV를 켜시면 됩니다. 어쨌든 경기가 시작되려고 합니다.
-Okay. -Shall we?
-좋아요. -그럴까요?
Yeah.
응.
Wait.
기다리다.
Where did that go?
그건 어디로 갔나요?
"That"?
"저것"?
You stupid eight-tailed fox. Didn't I warn you about humans?
멍청한 여덟 꼬리 여우야. 내가 인간에 대해 경고하지 않았나요?
Especially men, of all people?
특히 남자들은요?
You didn't!
당신은하지 않았습니다!
-I didn't? -No.
- 난 안 그랬어? -아니요.
I don't think you said that.
나는 당신이 그런 말을 한 것 같지 않습니다.
Do I have to spell it out for you?
내가 당신을 위해 그것을 철자해야합니까?
How would I know if you didn't say it?
당신이 말하지 않았다면 내가 어떻게 알겠어요?
Just wait a second!
잠시만 기다려주세요!
Please!
제발!
Just calm down.
진정하세요.
Why should I?
왜 그래야 합니까?
Come on, what is it? Let's calmly talk about it.
자, 그게 뭐죠? 그것에 대해 침착하게 이야기합시다.
How does blowing up like that help anything?
어떻게 그렇게 터지나요? 뭐 도와줄까?
You look exactly like her, and you even act just like her.
당신은 그녀와 꼭 닮았어요 그리고 당신도 그 사람처럼 행동해요.
Listen to me carefully.
내 말을 잘 들어보세요.
I won't stop you from becoming human.
나는 당신이 인간이 되는 것을 막지 않을 것이다.
But men?
그런데 남자?
Do you know how many women ruin their lives over men?
여자가 몇명인지 아시나요? 남자 때문에 인생을 망치나요?
-Especially naive girls like you. -Hey.
-특히 너처럼 순진한 여자들은. -여기요.
Girls like you need to be extra careful around men.
너 같은 여자애들 남자 주변에서는 특히 조심해야 해요.
Then what about you?
그렇다면 당신은 어떻습니까?
What?
무엇?
I saw everything.
나는 모든 것을 보았다.
You held hands,
당신은 손을 잡았고,
and last night at Namsan…
그리고 어젯밤 남산에서…
That's… different.
그건… 다르다.
How so?
어떻게요?
I'm going back to how I was, and this guy…
다시 예전으로 돌아가는데 이 사람은…
is decent and great at soccer,
착하고 축구도 잘하고,
despite how he looks now.
그가 지금 어떻게 생겼는지에도 불구하고.
But look at you.
하지만 당신을보세요.
You barely know that guy, so why are you stalking him?
당신은 그 사람을 거의 알지 못합니다. 그럼 왜 그 사람을 스토킹하는 거야?
What do you even see in him?
그에게서 무엇을 보나요?
His face.
그의 얼굴.
Come again?
또 오세요?
He's good-looking.
그는 잘 생겼어요.
See? This is exactly why I'm worried.
보다? 이것이 바로 제가 걱정하는 이유입니다.
Do you think his looks are going to pay the bills?
그의 외모가 생각나나요? 청구서를 지불 할 예정입니까?
Why are you so against this?
왜 이렇게 반대하시나요?
Let her like him. She'll learn from it.
그녀가 그를 좋아하게 해주세요. 그녀는 그것으로부터 배울 것입니다.
You said he's broke, and she's clueless!
당신은 그가 돈이 없다고 말했고 그녀는 아무것도 모릅니다!
He should at least have something if he's going to take care of that idiot.
그 사람은 적어도 뭔가는 갖고 있어야 해 그 사람이 그 바보를 처리할 거라면.
Of all the men out there…
거기 있는 남자들 중에...
Isn't there anyone else?
다른 사람은 없나요?
Sorry to interrupt.
방해해서 죄송합니다.
Right. What about him?
오른쪽. 그 사람은 어때요?
At least he isn't broke.
적어도 그는 파산하지 않았습니다.
What?
무엇?
Jeong-bae, what's up?
정배야, 무슨 일이야?
Well, it's just that we think you've been robbed.
뭐, 그냥 그렇구나 우리는 당신이 강도를 당했다고 생각합니다.
Robbed?
강도를 당했나요?
Weird.
기이한.
Do thieves these days
요즘 도둑들아
steal the AC off the wall?
벽에서 AC를 훔쳐?
Jeez, that was the only thing in this house worth any money.
이런, 그거 뿐이었어 이 집에서는 돈만큼 가치가 있어요.
How did they know to take that?
그 사람들이 그걸 어떻게 받아들일지 알았나요?
Si-yeol, is there anything else you're missing?
시열아, 거기 있어? 또 뭐 빠진 거 있어?
I don't know. Eun-ho.
모르겠습니다. 은호.
Are you missing anything?
혹시 빠진 것이 있나요?
Just out of curiosity…
단지 호기심으로…
did that thing double as a heater?
그거 히터 겸용이었어?
No, not really.
아니요, 그렇지 않습니다.
Right? That's a relief.
오른쪽? 다행이네요.
What's with that reaction?
그 반응은 어떻습니까?
So, about the AC,
AC에 관해서는,
-I sold it. -What?
- 팔았어요. -무엇?
We won't be here in the summer anyway.
어쨌든 우리는 여름에 여기에 없을 거예요.
It's winter and it's freezing.
겨울이고 춥습니다.
So it's not like we'll need AC, right?
그럼 AC가 필요한 건 아니겠죠?
That's true.
그것은 사실이다.
Good job. We're broke anyway.
잘했어요. 어쨌든 우리는 파산했습니다.
-So that's where the cash came from? -Yeah.
-그럼 현금은 거기서 나왔나요? -응.
Oh, I see.
알겠어요.
I guess you sold it.
판매하셨나 봅니다.
Well, as long as you weren't robbed.
글쎄, 당신이 강도를 당하지 않는 한.
-Yeah. -Right.
-응. -오른쪽.
How much did you get for it, Eun-ho?
은호야 얼마 받았어?
-What? -She gave me 200,000 won.
-무엇? - 20만원을 줬어요.
You sold it for 200,000 won?
20만원에 팔았나요?
Why? Was it worth more?
왜? 더 가치가 있었나요?
That was the latest model he bought this summer.
최신모델이었는데 그는 이번 여름에 샀어요.
It's worth at least 400,000 won.
최소 40만원 정도의 가치가 있습니다.
At least 400,000?
최소 400,000?
Wait. What about the outdoor unit?
기다리다. 실외기는 어떻습니까?
Did you sell that too?
그것도 팔았나요?
Yeah, because you don't need it without the AC.
응, 너한테는 필요 없으니까 AC 없이.
They said they'd get rid of it for me,
나를 위해 없애주겠다고 하더군요.
even though you usually have to pay for that.
그래도 일반적으로 그 비용을 지불해야 합니다.
The outdoor unit alone must be worth over 50,000 won.
실외기는 단독으로 5만원 이상이어야 합니다.
Maybe even 100,000 won.
어쩌면 10만원이라도.
Did you say 100,000 won? People sell those too?
10만원이라고 했나? 사람들이 그것도 팔아요?
Did I just get scammed?
나만 사기당한 걸까?
Hey, are you okay?
이봐, 괜찮아?
What?
무엇?
Why are you so tense?
왜 그렇게 긴장해요?
It's not your first time on the national team.
처음이 아니잖아 국가대표에서.
Right. Maybe it's because I've always dreamed of this.
오른쪽. 아마도 그 이유는 나는 항상 이것을 꿈꿔 왔습니다.
But my heartbeat feels strange.
그런데 심장박동이 이상한 것 같아요.
What are you talking about?
무슨 얘기를 하는 건가요?
Don't be nervous. We got this.
긴장하지 마세요. 우리는 이것을 얻었습니다.
Jeez.
이런.
Why is everyone drinking booze like water in front of me today?
왜 다들 술을 마시고 있는 걸까? 오늘 내 앞에 물처럼?
If you're going to drink, at least eat something with it. Okay?
술 마실 예정이라면, 적어도 그것으로 뭔가를 먹어라. 좋아요?
Here.
여기.
Why are you so upset? These things happen.
왜 그렇게 화가 났나요? 이런 일이 일어납니다.
Si-yeol.
시열.
Living as a human is just too hard.
인간으로 산다는 것은 너무 힘든 일이다.
What?
무엇?
Are you crying? You should stop drinking.
울고 있나요? 술을 끊어야 합니다.
I was just trying to do things right.
나는 단지 일을 제대로 하려고 노력하고 있었을 뿐입니다.
That's why I took the job at the store.
그래서 나는 가게에서 일을 맡았습니다.
But they worked me all day, called me useless, and didn't pay me.
하지만 그들은 하루 종일 나에게 일을 했고, 나를 쓸모없다고 말하며 돈을 주지 않았습니다.
Then they told me to pay back 49,850 won.
그랬더니 49,850원을 갚으라고 하더군요.
What? Which store was that?
무엇? 어느 가게였나요?
Are they insane?
미친거니?
So I tried to fix it by selling used stuff online,
그래서 고쳐보려고 했는데 중고물품을 온라인으로 판매함으로써
but I got scammed doing that too.
그런데 나도 그렇게 하다가 사기를 당했어요.
I really can't live like this anymore.
이제 정말 이렇게는 못 살겠어요.
Come on, Eun-ho.
자, 은호야.
Eun-ho, it's okay.
은호야, 괜찮아.
It's okay.
괜찮아요.
You don't have to be here with me. Go inside and watch the game.
당신은 나와 함께 여기있을 필요가 없습니다. 안으로 들어가서 경기를 지켜보세요.
The international match starts soon, doesn't it?
이제 곧 국제경기가 시작되는데, 그렇지 않습니까?
What's the point of me watching that?
내가 그걸 보는 게 무슨 소용이 있지?
I know Woo-seok is playing instead of me,
나 대신 우석이가 노는 걸 알지만,
but I don't exactly want to watch it myself.
하지만 난 정확히는 그렇지 않아 직접 보고 싶어요.
It's hard for you too, right? I'm sorry.
당신도 힘들죠? 죄송합니다.
Eun-ho, I didn't say that to make you cry.
은호야, 널 울리려고 그런 말을 한 건 아니다.
Don't worry.
괜찮아요.
I promise I'll get you back to your old life, okay?
널 다시 데려올 거라고 약속할게 옛 생활로 돌아가, 알았지?
I really promise.
정말 약속해요.
What?
무엇?
We're doing just fine.
우리는 잘 지내고 있어요.
Let's not worry too much.
너무 걱정하지 말자.
Si-yeol!
시열!
Something big happened!
큰 일이 일어났어요!
What happened?
무슨 일이에요?
Hey, Si-yeol!
안녕하세요, 시열님!
Hyeon Woo-seok collapsed!
현우석이 쓰러졌다!
What?
무엇?
He collapsed right before the match.
그는 경기 직전에 쓰러졌다.
-Woo-seok! -Hey, Woo-seok!
-우석! -야, 우석아!
-Coach!
-코치!
Apparently, it was cardiac arrest.
분명히 심장 마비였습니다.
They say he might die.
죽을 수도 있다고 합니다.
What did you say?
뭐라고 하셨나요?
Woo-seok!
우석!
Hey, wake up. Come on!
이봐, 일어나. 어서 해봐요!
Damn it!
젠장!
Over here!
여기요!
Eun-ho, what's happening right now?
은호 씨, 지금 무슨 일이 일어나고 있나요?
-Why is Woo-seok… -I don't know.
- 우석이는 왜… - 모르겠어요.
I just switched your fates. That's all.
나는 방금 당신의 운명을 바꿨습니다. 그게 다야.
I'm not sure what's happening.
무슨 일이 일어나고 있는지 잘 모르겠습니다.
Wait.
기다리다.
Then, what just happened to Woo-seok
그렇다면 우석에게는 무슨 일이 있었던 걸까?
was the fate that was meant for me?
나에게 주어진 운명이었나?
Am I the reason he ended up like this?
그 사람이 이렇게 된 건 나 때문일까?
Woo-seok might die instead of me?
우석이가 나 대신 죽을 수도 있다?
If that's true, what happens now?
그것이 사실이라면 이제 어떻게 될까요?
If you go back to normal, can we reverse all this?
다시 원래대로 돌아가면, 이 모든 것을 되돌릴 수 있나요?
I can't reverse it.
나는 그것을 되돌릴 수 없습니다.
What?
무엇?
Charging 150 joules.
150 줄을 충전합니다.
One, two, clear!
하나, 둘, 클리어!
Charging 200 joules. One, two, clear!
200 줄을 충전합니다. 하나, 둘, 클리어!
I can't reverse it.
나는 그것을 되돌릴 수 없습니다.
If your friend dies in your place,
당신의 친구가 당신 대신 죽는다면,
there's nothing I can do, even if I'm back to normal.
내가 할 수 있는 일은 아무것도 없어, 내가 다시 정상으로 돌아온다고 해도.
There's no way for me to reverse your fate
네 운명을 되돌릴 수 있는 방법은 없어
or to bring your friend back.
아니면 친구를 다시 데려오거나.
SPECIAL APPEARANCE BY HONG SU-HYEON
홍수현 특별출연
NO TAIL TO TELL
말할 꼬리가 없습니다
Did you think tampering with human fate was a trivial matter?
인간의 운명을 조작한다고 생각했나요? 사소한 일이었어?
Let's switch back now.
이제 다시 전환해 보겠습니다.
It's not possible right now.
지금은 불가능합니다.
Why isn't it possible now?
지금은 왜 불가능합니까?
You know it too, don't you? That you're going to die soon.
당신도 알고 있지 않습니까? 당신은 곧 죽을 것입니다.
I wouldn't sell this for all the gold in the world.
나는 이것을 팔지 않을 것이다 세상의 모든 금을 위해.
-Who are you? -I didn't expect to find
-누구세요? -찾을 줄은 몰랐어
another one hiding in a place like this.
이런 곳에 또 한 마리가 숨어 있다.
Fix this twisted fate with your own two hands.
이 뒤틀린 운명을 고쳐줘 당신의 두 손으로.
You want me to just die instead of Si-yeol?
넌 내가 그냥 죽기를 바라잖아 시열 대신?
So I need you to help me.
그래서 당신이 나를 도와줘야 해요.
Subtitle translation by Susanna Kim
김수잔나님의 자막 번역